# **OLIVIA DAVIES**

Retail Sales Associate

**T** 05911 135476

E olivia.davies@gmail.com

▲ Texas.US

L linkedin.com/in/olivia.davies

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Dedicated Sales Associate with 5+ years of experience in retail environments. Recognised for my ability to communicate with customers, provide exceptional service, and upsell products. Have received 'Employee of the Year' award two years consecutively. Seeking a retail sales position with opportunities for advancement into a managerial position.

#### **EDUCATION**

• University of Leeds (2014-2017) BA (Hons) Business Management, upper second class honours (2:1)

Relevant Modules Management Research and Analysis, Managing in the Digital

Workplace, Operations and Supply Chain Management, Leadership

in Organisations, Strategic Management

**Dissertation Topic** Implementation of Effective Sales Strategies

King Edward VII - A-levels: Maths (A), French (A), English Literature (A)

**Upper School,** GCSEs: 10 A-C including Maths, English, Combined Science, and

Sheffield (2007-2014) Geography

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### BURBERRY, Soho, London

Sales Associate

December 2018 - Present

- Assist ~50 customers daily in finding merchandise, while providing recommendations that have led to a 12% annual increase in sales
- Helped implement a new inventory tracking system, improving organisational efficiency
- Exceeded sales goals by over 150% for two consecutive months
- Manage merchandise displays, highlighting new inventory with the goal of increasing sales
- Regularly maintain at least a 90% customer service feedback rating
- Encouraged 80 new patrons to sign up for Burberry's newsletter
- Received 'Employee of the Year' awards for 2019 and 2020

**DEBENHAMS, Leeds** *Retail Sales Associate* 

May 2017 - November 2018

- Repeatedly exceeded monthly sales quotas
- Drove up sales by upselling new merchandise and making informed recommendations
- Memorised Debenhams' product inventory in order to provide better advice to customers
- Operated Point of Sales systems efficiently
- Fielded customer complaints and offered workable solutions, leading to a 10% decrease in full refunds
- Maintained a consistent 'A' rating in customer experience satisfaction surveys

## TESCO, Leeds

May 2015 - March 2017

Customer Assistant

- Checked out upwards of 150 customers daily, ensuring they each had a seamless, pleasant experience
- Led a drive to reduce food waste, earning accolades from management for efficiency and environmental consciousness
- Ensured all produce was handled according to health and safety regulations
- Maintained accurate records of store inventory

### **KEY SKILLS**

Expert organisational skills - Skilled with Point of Sale software (TokenWorks Magnetic Card Reader, Plexis Software Plexis POS) - Conversational French speaker - Upselling - Excellent interpersonal skills - Conflict resolution - Time management

#### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Avid cyclist, regularly participating in regional races - Amateur viola player - Enjoy socialising with friends